Well, usually before you go to the bed, you have to take him to do pee pee.
Yeah, we did.
But I guess he still got nervous when he was in the car.
And he likes to stick his head out the window.
¿Sí?
Sí.
Pero tengan cuidado porque se puede salir.
No, because we put it really high, high enough for only his head.
Sometimes he might put his feet.
Un pedacito de cristal.
But he can't get out.
Y nada más con un pedacito chiquitico de cristal.
No, it's about, um, his hands could touch the top.
And it's high enough for him to put his hands.
And do you hold him?
Yeah, I hold him. But I think that they're high enough so that él no se...
Paula, be careful, because si él ve un gato or something,
he might jump out of the car after the cat.
Chill.
Be careful.
Yeah, but I don't think, because he sees people all the time in the cars.
Sí, people, sí. But he never has seen a cat.
Tú te imaginas si ve un gato.
¿Qué pasa?
He's seen one before.
Well, you never know.
You have to be careful.
I know.
Well, tell me, ¿qué pasó con el voleibol ese tuyo?
¿Cómo fue? Que tú has entrado en el team de voleibol, muchacha.
¿Quién te enseñó a ti a jugar a voleibol?
I don't know.
Yo creo que es una pasión.
It's like, it's a passion already for me.
Did you play volleyball at the other school you were in?
We did. Pero it was completely different.
It didn't work out.
They changed the entire game.
Did they have a team there?
In my old school?
Yeah, they did.
And, tú sabes, it wasn't the same.
Pero now I actually get to go into a team where I actually
get to play the game.
And you know, I was so nervous. Because I wasn't sure if I was gonna
be able to, you know, entrar el team,
like if I was gonna make it.
Because I was around so many like awesome players.
Y ya fueron.
Pero me dijo tu mamá con la niña que before was in the team, she didn't make it?
She didn't make it.
How come?
I don't know.
I think it was because she wasn't doing so good.
I'm not sure, 'cause maybe that's what they thought.
Pero I thought ella fue like very good.
¿Ella fue buena jugando?
Sí, fue buena, muy buena.
¿Buena?
¿Y por qué no la cogieron?
Maybe it was be... I don't know, maybe it was because
that she had her grades low.
Because if you have an F, or maybe more than one F,
you can't go into the team.
Maybe. But maybe that's not the reason.
Maybe they just didn't like her.
Or maybe they had better players.
And when do you have to practice?
We have to practice, uh, every week, um, school day.
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday.
I mean, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday.
¿Y a qué hora?
Monday, Tuesday, Thursday, and Friday at seven forty-five.
Seven forty-five in the morning?
Yes.
And who's gonna take you?
I will, if nobody will take you.
Look, I'm not gonna get up that early.
No, probably mami and papi.
Ah, bueno, sí.
Porque papi va temprano para trabajo.
Y te deja ahí. Cuando te deja, ¿hay gente en la escuela?
Well, there will be other girls that are on the team there
waiting.
¿Y la maestra?
She'll be coming in at the same time.
Paula, y...
There are teachers coming in at that time already.
Oh, they do?
Yeah, but they're not there outside.
They're inside preparing for school to start.
Inside the building?
Yeah.
And we're outside.
And how do you get through the office when you go outside?
Well, we go through the bus loop.
And the parents drop us off there.
What's the bus loop?
Where the bus is for the kids that go on the bus.
They drop the kids off.
Where I leave you every morning?
The same place I leave you?
No, on the other side.
¿Dónde los niños juegan por la tablita esa?
¿La patineta esa que yo veo?
Oh, no, no, no, the other side where all the buses are.
Oh, in the back.
Yeah.
That way we're closer to the school.
And I don't have to walk that far.
¿Y después, de qué hora a qué hora vas a hacer la práctica?
It's an hour.
So if I start at seven forty-five, I end at eight forty-five.
¿Y después se pueden bañar ahí?
I don't think so.
¿Y ustedes llevan ropa para cambiarse?
Yeah, the school clothes.
Imagínate qué rollo.
¿Tiene que llevar la ropa en un puchero?
No, we just stick 'em in our book bags.
Bueno, ¿un jean?
Jean and a polo shirt.
Y entonces para la práctica, ¿qué llevas? ¿Un short y un t-shirt?
We are gonna take the shorts and any type of shirt
with our knee pads.
Ay, ay, yo vi los kneepads.
Son como unos elásticos, ¿no, Paula?
Yeah.
Yo pensé que eran sobre un casco plástico duro.
You're crazy!
Yeah, but that's not the same, because if you go on the floor,
you can really hurt yourself with those.
Es más que hurt yourself.
Probably you can hurt the wood in that place.
That's why.
Sí, donde juegan béisbol, básquetbol, ¿no?
Yeah.
Oh.
So I'm not gonna be seeing you every morning then?
No.
Only Wednesdays?
Only Wednesdays and maybe on the weekends.
Maybe on weekends.
So who's gonna fix your breakfast?
Who's gonna fix your lunch?
Bueno, I'm probably gonna
have to start eating at the school.
Breakfast and lunch?
Only Wednesdays.
Only Wednesdays you can make me lunch.
Entonces then I will not be buying any stuff for you this weekend.
OK, Monday you're gonna go to practice?
OK, so Wednesday is the only day.
And what I do, I get you a little bit of ham
and maybe a croissant.
Sí.
Un cruasán.
Y la papita, y la jugo de manzana, y agüita.
Oh my god.
Agüita, Paula, ¿no la beben, agüita?
Maybe I can take some agüitas to you.
And you can put it in your bag.
Maybe.
Oh my goodness, abuela.
Everything hurts.
Everything hurts?
You're an old lady.
I know I am.
A qué voleibol ese...
¿Te duele el cucu?
Everything hurts.
Yes, that too.
That too?
Mi madre.
Estás muy grave. Estás en bad shape.
I think it was because I did thirty squats
and I haven't done squats in forever.
¿Qué cosas son los squats?
Well, you have to bend your knees and go up and down.
A ver, show me.
Be careful!
Be careful.
Show me.
OK.
One.
Ah, y ¿para qué es eso?
It's good because it makes your muscles stronger
and it keeps you in shape.
Yo creo que eso también te va a hacer crecer el cucu.
Yo te veo.
OK, abuela.
Random.
Oye, y las niñas que están en el team,
¿hay algunas que son very close friends of yours, or no?
Well, the one that was supposed to make it on the team, she was,
but no.
I think I only have one friend.
One friend in the team?
¿Y hay muchos negritos?
There's only two.
¿Dos negritas?
Are they your friends?
No, I don't know them.
Y do you have any classes with them?
No.
Nadie en el team tú tienes clase?
Well, um, with one of them I do.
So...
Cuéntame, ¿cómo a ti te gusta el colegio este?
¿Cómo tú comparas este colegio con el colegio anterior?
How do you like it?
I like it.
It's better than my old school.
Y the people are so much nicer.
They are nicer here?
Yes.
Who, the teachers or the children?
No, everybody.
Really?
Yeah.
It's a lot tougher.
A lot tougher.
You mean the material?
Educational.
Um, no, no, no, the, um...
The curriculum.
Yeah, the curriculum is harder, a lot harder.
Testing, not as much as before.
OK.
Less testing.
Pero more projects.
You had more testing than here?
Yeah. We don't have to do spelling in this school.
No?
At all.
Don't you have any class that say spelling?
No.
Y tú ¿cómo tú aprendes el spelling de las palabras?
We don't have it.
Do you have history?
We have geography.
¿Y historia?
No, we have geography.
It's more like the map of the countries.
Sí.
It's not as much about history.
It's not like we're learning about George Washington
and Abraham Lincoln.
And we're learning more about cultures this year
and different cultures from different countries and continents.
Like the other day we were learning about Russia.
Mmhm.
¿Y qué aprendiste?
Um...
Aparte de que los rusos no se bañan.
They don't?
No, they don't, because it's very, very cold where they live.
And usually they don't bath every day.
I have a friend...
Maybe they bath once a week.
Even if we are lucky.
I have a friend from Russia.
If she lives here, es distinto.
Porque entonces ya se baña, porque aquí calor.
Yeah, she lives in New York.
And I met her on the cruise.
Do you remember the one we went on?
Oh, which cruise?
In the one from, um, the Royal Caribbean.
Oh, the, el, el de Freedom?
Yeah, that one.
The Freedom?
We had fun there.
It was fun.
Oh, yeah.
And I liked that thing, that board thingy, the Flowrider.
Mhmm.
When I got on my knees, it was so much fun.
Y em, yeah...
Y the people there were so nice on the cruise.
Y la comida, the pizza there was awesome.
Yeah, remember how much pizza we ate?
And it was like an all you can eat pizza.
Y la galletica.
La galletica.
Oh my god.
¿Te acuerdas todas las galleticas que trajimos a abuela?
Yeah.
Que guardamos galleticas.
Trajimos galleticas a abuela.
And the desserts.
They had a tiramisú.
Tiramisú.
Which one did you like best, the Freedom or the one that we went, Costa, at the end of the year?
Fortuna?
The Fortuna.
Um, I liked Freedom more.
But I liked the food in Fortuna more.
Fortuna was good.
La comida fue...
Maravillosa.
Como comimos tan rico.
Mhmm.
Oh, I'm getting hungry.
Yeah.
Ah, no.
Definitely not.
I think we ate so much this morning.
It wasn't not even funny.
Are you feeling OK now?
Better.
OK, good.
Pero la comida, los pancakes de blueberry.
Después con el hash brown casserole, two sunny side up eggs.
Las tostadas.
Y jugo de naranja.
Oh god.
But then fuimos a caminar por el mall.
Y entonces se te bajó la comida.
Oh goodness, I wish I was still there.
Ay, como bien bonito, Paula.
Yeah.
I loved the stores there.
Son todos diferentes.
Y el em, fuimos a Love Culture que estaba bonito.
Mhmm.
Fuimos a Zoomies.
Em, fuimos al Coldwater Creek.
A Coldwater.
Mhmm.
Y ah, Origins.
Em, ¿cuál otra?
Yo creo que eso fue.
No, y fuimos también al lugar ese de la aprendecita.
¿Briden?
¿Burkden o algo así?
Y también we were outside looking window shopping in Black and White.
Ay, Black and White.
Y Ann Taylor.
Ann Taylor Loft.
Oh, that Black and White, the dress.
That black, black dress, oh.
That black dress with the...
Yes.
It was beautiful.
Very.
Eso estaba tan lindo.
But the dress you bought was beautiful.
Sí.
It's beautiful.
I like it.
I love the black and the top and the flowers on the bottom.
Mhmm, mhmm.
It's very...
Modern.
Está muy juvenil.
Es muy de primavera, de verano.
Está bonito, bien bonito.
Yeah, está muy modern y nuevo.
Sí, sí.
That's the new thing.
A new style ahora es, like, flores and...
Sí.
Y así que parece no se pega al cuerpo porque...
It's kind of...
Pero now they have a new style que se llama neutral, que son como los colors...
I know it's kind of mean, pero it's kind of boring colors.
Like beige and that.
Like beige and, like, pale white.
Ah, bueno, sí, los neutrals son colores que pegan con cualquier cosa.
Yeah, like...
Um...
Yeah, all the beiges and the white, off-white, white, eh, dirty, dirty, dirty white.
Yeah.
There's a dirty white.
Dirty white.
Those are nice.
Even black is neutral.
Sort of.
Mhmm.
And now they have all the skinny jeans are in style.
El...
¿Cómo es skinny y qué es eso?
Skinny jeans are, ah, los jeans que son muy, muy pegaditos.
¿Y son estrech?
No.
¿No son estrech?
Nope.
¿Y como son pegaditos no son estrech?
¿No te puedes mover entonces?
¿No te puedes sentar?
Yeah, you can.
They're just a lot more closer to the skin.
Very close.
Pero eso te da un calor?
No, they actually, they, they don't.
No?
No.
¿Tú tienes algunos?
Yeah, I have a pair from American Eagle.
Oh, OK.
And another pair from Forever Twenty-one que son muy lindos.
¿Qué cosa es Forever Twenty-one?
It's a store in, in almost every mall que tiene in America.
OK.
Or the United States, at least.
Y ¿de dónde hay eso? ¿En Pembroke Pines mall?
They have it in Pembroke Pines.
They have it in, um...
What else do they have them in?
They have 'em in the Sawgrass mall, the Dolphin mall.
Where did you buy it?
Oh, the jeans?
Uhuh.
I bought 'em in, um, Pembroke Pines mall, I think.
Ay Paula, you know what?
Eh, cerraron el Franquitu que está delante del cine.
For real?
Yeah, they close all Franquitus.
There's only one open, the one downtown.
Downtown?
Why?
They weren't doing good business?
They weren't doing good business, no.
Esto, los tuvieron que cerrar.
Están sacando todos los muebles.
Ha sido un desastre.
What do you think that they're gonna put there?
I don't know.
Probably another little restaurant.
Es que el Franquitu era muy caro.
Los hot dogs eran muy caros entonces.
And they, they were OK.
They weren't all that great.
Yeah, but Paula, very expensive.
For a hot dog.
I remember that one day we went.
Y compramos un hot dog tú, un hot dog yo, papitas, tú agua,
y yo unas boniáticos esos, sweet potato, y un té,
and it was like thirteen, fourteen dollars.
Thirteen, fourteen?
Yeah, that's very expensive for a hot dog this small.
I mean, when you go to Costco, for a dollar fifty,
they give you a hot dog this big.
Like a foot longer.
Y todas las Coca Colas que quieres tomar, por, por un dólar con cincuenta centavos.
I know.
Todo, sí.
It's not worth it.
Por dos o tres de pesos vamos a Cubanito.
Pon un arroz, frijoles, bistec, o si no arroz, frijoles, picadillos.
Uh, qué hambre tengo.
You're not hungry, Paula?
No.
Ay, Paula.
So, um, abuela, tell me.
Bueno, Paula, tú sabes que la semana que viene se acaba el colegio.
Viene las vacaciones de Easter.
So excited.
But isn't it already gonna be this week
that's gonna be Easter?
El domingo es Easter.
Pero como tú vas a un colegio público,
ellos no lo unen con las fiestas religiosas.
Lo posponen una semana.
Entonces, ¿qué tú vas a hacer semana?
¿Te vas a ir conmigo para que trabajes?
I think so.
And then maybe I might go with mom some days to work.
Está bien.
And maybe I might go visit my friends in my old school, hopefully.
No, that would be fun.
Yeah.
And that way they could see me.
I haven't seen them in a while.
Yeah, that'd be fun.
And maybe I can go hang out with my best friend.
Who's your best friend?
Joanna.
Ay sí, Joanna's nice.
I like Joanna.
Me too.
She's very nice.
She's a very nice girl.
Mhmm.
And she's not mean.
You could tell her anything.
Yeah, she's a sweet girl.
Yeah.
She's very sweet.
She always pays attention to you.
She never leaves you out.
Y eso también.
Ella, ella es buena amiguita tuya, ¿eh?
Mhmm.
Los pantalones que tú tenías puesto eran de ella?
I know.
You told me.
Y el t-shirt. De Abercrombie.
Ay, el t-shirt también?
¿Cuál?
¿El que tenías puesto hoy?
No, el cual yo estaba usando para dormir.
Ay, y para dormir nada menos.
Te pones la ropa de Joanna para dormir.
Voy a tener...
No, it's just...
¿Por qué tú haces eso, Paula?
¿Y por qué estás sin vergüenza?
Well, she doesn't, she doesn't...
I don't have to give it back to her until next week.
Why?
Because she's with her dad now.
Ah, this weekend she's with her dad?
Yeah.
The long weekend.
Ella, probablemente ella la semana que viene sin clase, ¿no?
No, she's doing her spring break now.
¿Ahora?
I think it's over already.
Esta semana que está caminando es el spring break de ella?
Yeah.
Oh.
Since she goes to a different type of school.
It's a Christian school.
Yeah.
Tú sabes que tu tío, este weekend, está por una finca.
Ellos tienen unos amigos en Gainesville que tienen una finca, que tiene twenty acres.
And in that farm, ellos tienen horses.
¿Y cómo se dice chivo?
Um, sheep?
No, goat.
Goat?
Oh, goats.
Goats.
Y tienen un burro, un mulo.
No, that's a donkey.
A donkey.
Tienen un donkey.
Y entonces, la señora se iba a ir fuera.
Y Annabel y Jaime, they were gonna go there and take care of all the animals.
So they had to feed the hens and the chicken, everything.
So they were...
A lo mejor lo muerden.
A lo mejor el mulo lo muerde a tu tío.
Yo no creo.
Y los perros iban a pegar con ellos.
Oh my god.
Pero he told me yesterday that it was kind of cold.
Que había frío.
Where was it again?
It's in Gainesville.
But it's like twenty minutes from where they live.
Oh.
So it's in the outside of Gainesville.
So it's not that far.
No, no, no, no, it's not far away.
But it's in the outside of Gainesville.
Y tú tío mandó ahora por correo un CD con todas las fotos de Ecuador.
Te acuerdas que aquel día que las vimos las...
Oh yeah.
A verlas otra vez.
Y dígame, how is he?
He's doing OK.
And Annabel too.
You know what they told me? Not now but a long time ago,
that when they came back, when they will come back from Ecuador,
Annabel was going to try to get pregnant.
So maybe anytime they say,
hey, we're expecting a baby!
Cualquier momento nos llaman que ya vamos a tener otro bebe en la familia.
I'm gonna have a cousin.
I'm gonna finally have a cousin.
Sí, tenemos que ir a Gainesville cuando eso pasa a conocer el baby.
Huh, oh yeah.
Tenemos que ir a Gainesville.
Van a hacer la cocina.
They are gonna redo the kitchen.
De ahí ellos hicieron el patio.
Le pusieron un deck de madera.
Era bonito el patio.
Y van a hacer la cocina.
Cuando ellos finish la cocina, vamos a ir allá un weekend
para ver todo lo que han hecho en la casa.
Han hecho el deck de madera.
They changed the roof of the house.
And they had done a lot of things in the house.
That's nice.
Yeah, that house is beautiful.
I like that house.
It's so cozy.
So cute.
Parece una casita de muñecas chiquitica.
Pero es tan linda.
And have you seen their backyard how pretty it is?
Mhmm.
All the beautiful flowers that they have.
Y...
Y eso que la Angie, la perrita de ellos, estaba comiendo las flores.
Todas las flores se las come.
Deja las matas sin flores.
Esa Angie, she's a trip.
She's so cute.
She's too much.
You know when they went in Ecuador?
Angie used to sleep with me.
Angie and Bella.
But Angie wouldn't let Bella to get close to me.
She's jealous.
Sí. Ella...
Y cuando estamos sentados en el sofá, Eduardo y yo, a nosotros.
Ella nunca ha acostado arriba a ti en la casa.
Yeah.
She always did.
But her head weighed more than her body entirely.
Yeah, she's very heavy.
Think her head just weighs more than me.
She is heavy.
Oye, esta noche es Don Francisco.
Hace tiempo que no ves el programa Don Francisco.
No, pero you know...
I don't know.
El otro día yo estaba en el play ese que, que tú me viste.
Aha.
You were good in there.
I like it.
I think you're gonna be an actress.
Hopefully.
Would you like to be one?
Oh yeah.
That's my dream.
Really, Paula?
Ay, Paula, todos los artistas pasan hambre, hijita.
Pasan hambre por dos motivos.
Primero, por no tener dinero.
Segundo, porque tienes que estar flaco.
Tu abuela Ana siempre está de dieta.
Ah, Ana cada día está más flaquita.
Ay mi madre, qué flaquita está Ana.
Yeah, but she's taking good care of herself now.
She's skinny.
¿Cuánto pesa Ana?
Creo que cien libras.
She, she weighs, I think, a hundred and fifteen pounds.
Not even that.
I think less than that.
I think she does.
Ah, my aunt weighs more than that.
Sí, tu tía pesa un poquito más.
So, abuela.
¿Quién te a ti artista?
Watch me.
You'll see me on the big screen soon.
In the big screen doing what, movies in Hollywood?
Movies.
And I think I would do TV shows.
Are you shaving your legs?
Yes.
Who told you to do so?
Mom said it was OK.
Paula, please.
Tú sabes una vez que tú empiezas a afeitarte que te salen cada vez más duro, más duro.
I know.
Mejor que hagas esa cosa así.
I don't do that.
Depilar.
Sí, hija.
Porque cuando te depilas, los pelos se ponen suavecitos.
Pero cuando te afeitas se ponen duros, duros, duros.
Too late now.
My god.
How long have you been doing it?
Ehm, since December.
Since December?
How come I didn't notice before?
Because I did it my first time in December before the cruise.
Before the cruise?
Ay, Paula.
Up to where are you shaving?
Oh, no, no.
Madre mía.
Así que tú quieres ser una artista?
Imagínate de hambre de morirás.
Yo.
And how do you know?
Porque todas las artistas tienen que estar flacas, hija, el televisor.
Mira, pobre Don Francisco, Don Francisco, nada más que come pitta bread con pollo.
El pobre hombre salen plumas.
Porque nada más que come pitta bread, pitta bread y pollo.
Speaking of pollo, have you been
to Chick-fil-A?
No.
You have to go there, abuela.
You like it?
Oh my goodness, the food there is awesome.
Abuelo estuvo ahí.
A abuelo le gustó.
Pero yo no sé, no sé, nunca se me ha ocurrido ir hasta un día ellos van.
Pero nunca se me ha ocurrido.
Que comer hoy porque yo tengo hambre.
You're crazy.
No, I'm not crazy.
Si comimos, a qué hora fue, a la una y diez o las cinco, las cinco de la tarde, y yo me comí un pan.
It's been only been four hours.
Only four hours?
Only five hours?
I'm hungry already.
I need to eat something.
You're a monster, abuela.
How could you say I'm a monster?
I'm hungry, not a monster.
Bueno, son, when people are hungry they become monsters, you know.
They do?
Be careful, I might eat you.
Oh god.
Would you like to go tomorrow
to that party that we're going?
Oh yeah.
Sí?
A ver si yo veo la...
A la muchachita esa?
Mhmm.
Sí, ella seguro que está ahí porque es su casa.
Entonces, Paula, eh, mejor es que vayas a tu casa a dormir.
Yeah.
Y te arregles en tu casa mañana.
Porque mañana viene Eva a hacer...
Entonces, ¿por qué Eva se vaya?
Yo te llamo.
Yo quise ir mañana a la iglesia para no tener que ir el domingo.
OK.
If we have to go Sunday to church...
I don't...
Maybe we go at twelve.
OK.
Even if it's in Spanish, but it doesn't matter.
Porque si no, nos tenemos que levantar muy temprano.
OK.
Porque probablemente el sábado, si vas a party con nosotros, vamos a venir tarde.
Tienes que dormir en la casa.
Entonces nos levantamos domingo.
Vamos a misa.
OK?
Y si quieres te llevo a tu casa o si...
Isn't it Easter Sunday then?
Sí.
OK, I'll see.
Pero quiero ir a misa domingo.
Yo sé, pero...
Lo bueno sería ir mañana.
Mañana es sábado.
A ver si pudiéramos ir a la misa que es como a la, es a las cinco y media.
Sí, Eva va a venir a las dos.
Vamos así a las cinco y media.
Pudiéramos ir a la misa de cinco y media a las seis y media.
Y ya no tenemos entonces que ir a misa domingo.
What time is it at, abuela?
Five thirty.
Now?
No, it's five fifteen.
Y em, let's see.
Dígame.
What are you thinking of doing when you go on that cruise that you told me about?
Ay, Paula, that cruise is gonna be fantastic.
Mira, we fly in Miami, London.
London?
London, yeah, it's in England.
England?
In England, yes.
It's Miami, London.
Hey...
In London we get the cruise.
I mean the el bote, el bote, el, el boat.
You go to the cruise.
You...
The boat.
The cruise.
The...
No, no.
Cruise ship.
¿Cómo se llama?
El, el naviero.
El barco, el barco, el barco.
El barco, yes.
Entonces el barco la primer día sale por la tarde como a las cinco de la tarde.
Y cruza el canal y llega a Francia.
Entonces...
The English Channel?
Yeah, the English channel.
Y cruza.
Y vamos entonces a Francia.
Entonces en Francia compramos un ticket, abuelo y yo,
que el tour demora como diez horas y media.
Y nos van a llevar desde el puerto hasta Paris.
Entonces en ese día incluye un viaje en un barco por el río Seine, y con un almuerzo.
Y ahí se ve la Torre Eiffel.
Se ve la Notre Dame church.
Vemos el Arco Triunfo.
Y, ¿cómo se llama el museo este importante?
The Guggenburgh?
El Louvre, el Louvre.
No.
Que cuando yo estuve hace dos años con Rose en, en Bélgica y en Francia, nosotros fuimos al Louvre.
Y entonces vamos, el, el tour cubre...
Está en la iglesia esa famosa que se llama la Sagrada Familia, la Sagrada, no, el Sagrado Corazón, que es precioso, precioso.
¿Qué tú quieres que te traiga de viaje?
Bring me a cup of tea from England.
A cup of tea from England.
Entonces...
No, bring me los cookies que they serve for the snack for the, the cookies and tea.
The England.
Tú sabes que, y este último viaje que nosotros fuimos el Costa?
Un día los estábamos buscando, no sé si a ti y a David, o we were looking for Rick and Diana.
I don't know.
We were looking for somebody.
And Eduardo and me, we saw people having tea and cookies.
So we got there.
What happened?
No, I'm just looking for something.
Oh, here it is.
Eh, we got there and we had tea and cookies like the English people at four o'clock.
At four o'clock, the time that they do too.
Yeah, I think, right?
That's the time.
It's between three thirty, five o'clock that they have tea.
So después que vayamos a Paris, el, el barco para en un puerto que se llama la Habre en el sur de Francia.
Después cruza a España.
Para en Bilbao.
Para en Gijon.
Después va a Lisboa.
Lisboa.
No.
Después vamos a Lisboa.
Lisboa está en Portugal.
Yo tengo muchas ganas de conocer a Lisboa.
Esa es uno de las cosas que más me...
Y ¿dónde es eso otra vez?
En Portugal.
Portugal.
OK, entonces después va...
No me acuerdo como se llaman los puertos que van por abajo.
Pero va a Sevilla.
Va a Valencia.
Y termina en Barcelona.
Barcelona.
Entonces regreso de Barcelona para acá el día de las madres.
El día de las madres es día que se acaba el viaje en el barco.
Y regresamos para acá.
That's nice.
It's gonna be fun.
Lo que va a haber un poco frío.
And, um, it's not a popular cruise ship?
Es en Celebrity Cruises.
Oh, it's Celebrity?
Celebrity, so you know how good the food is gonna be.
Oh my goodness.
Oh my god!
They make the best.
Sí.
I've heard.
Y hacen unos dulces.
Los dulces que hace esa Celebrity...
Fíjate, Celebrity tiene five star kitchen.
Los chefs de Celebrity are the very best.
The best of the best.
The very best.
Nosotros hemos ido en Celebrity, a uno que fue catorce días a cruzar el canal de Panamá, y otro que fue catorce días que fuimos.
Salió de Buenos Aires.
Y terminó en Chile.
Y pasó por el polo sur.
Y vimos la antártica.
Y vimos los...
¿Cómo se llama eso?
Los glaciales.
Precioso.
Pero la comida es fabulosa.
Speaking of Chile, have you spoken to, um, eh, Rodrigo y...
Rodrigo estaba, está aquí.
Rodrigo estuvo aquí toda la semana.
Se va mañana.
O se va esta noche.
Y las niñas estuvieron aquí todo el mes de enero y febrero.
Pero ahora están en el colegio.
And from what time do they start school at, do you know?
They start school at...
Because I have a different schedule.
Yeah, they have different schedules.
They start school in March first, until December fifteenth.